ESHAN JAIRATH

Location: New Delhi, India | Tel: +91 8800118911 | Email: eshanjairath@outlook.com | GitHub | Linked In | Portfolio

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS | SUMMARY

Intelligent, ambitious, and talented engineer with exceptional computer science skills worked for small start-ups in Artificial Intelligence and software engineering departments. Gained experience in managing teams and building applications from scratch by working on a variety of small and large-scale projects.

EDUCATION

- MSc. Artificial Intelligence, Northumbria University, Newcastle, United Kingdom, 2021-2022.
- B. Tech. Computer Science Engineering, SRM University, Delhi NCR, India, 2016-2020.

WORK AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Academic Research, Northumbria University, Newcastle, (July 2022- Sept 2022)

• Conducted academic research on flood extent prediction using geospatial data extracted from the google earth engine and build a machine-learning regression model which acquired an NSE (Nash–Sutcliffe model efficiency coefficient) of 0.83 and RMSE of 0.27.

Junior Al Engineer, Print it Out, New Delhi, India, (May 2021 – Aug 2021)

- Gathering the necessary facial data, pre-processing it, training, testing, and evaluating the models in real-world scenarios by detecting the faces of the team members in real time.
- Boosted the Accuracy of the face detection algorithm to 91% on the testing data by choosing the right configuration of the necessary computer vision model and certain image pre-processing techniques.

Software Engineer, Pixxmo, New Delhi, India, (Nov 2020 – May 2021)

- Developed system analysis reports and system designs in accordance with the requirements of the projects after closely collaborating with clients and various teams.
- Reduced the workload of the entire team by 50% by employing Third-party cloud APIs in the systems and building software/Applications according to the finalized system designs and reports.

SKILLS-

- **Programming** Python, JavaScript.
- Data Structures and Algorithms.
- Web React.js (Redux and context API), Node, Express.js, REST API.
- Database MongoDB, SQL, Firebase.
- Cloud Microsoft Azure
- Version Control Git and GitHub

- Data Visualization Microsoft Power Bl.
- System Analysis and Design
- Problem Solving.
- Machine learning & deep learning Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Pandas, computer vision, Neural Networks, NLP, Reinforcement learning, ELT pipelines.

CERTIFICATIONS -

- Azure DP-100 (02/2023) Microsoft
- Azure AI-900 (05/2022) Microsoft
- Azure DP-900 (06/2022) Microsoft

- Python programming (03/2020) -Udemy
- Machine learning (06/2021) *Udemy*
- Deep learning (08/2021) Udemy

PROJECTS-

- A web application that uses a machine learning classification model to assist doctors and medical teams in predicting Heart Failure for a patient. The Flask web application is hosted on Heroku. *Project Link, GitHub Repo.*
- A CNN (Convolution Neural Network) model trained on the CIFAR-10 dataset, which gives 86% accuracy on the test set and manages to predict random images from every category in the dataset correctly. *GitHub Repo.*
- A fraud detection system using SOM which gives 87% accuracy in identifying credit card fraud and returns the customer IDs of the fraudulent customers. *GitHub Repo.*
- React web Application that uses TMDB API to showcase the latest movies and TV shows. Project Link, GitHub Repo.
- Instagram clone named Pics Watch made with react.js and firebase for user authentication. <u>Project Link</u>, <u>GitHub Repo.</u>